# **CLIVE MACHADO | Frontend Engineer**

'OASIS', Vasai, Mumbai, India - 401201 | +919673174211 / +919359419871 | clivemchd@gmail.com

#### **OBJECTIVE:**

Highly focused and passionate software engineer having 4 years experience working as an Application Engineer. Strongly motivated and possess an organised way to approach a problem and provide detailed results. Enthusiastic & supportive team player with a can-do attitude, ready to take responsibility for core components being developed and resolve project related issues. Ability to think out-of-the-box in complex situations to provide a unique and feasible solution.

## **SKILLS:**

Javascript | ReactJS | React-Redux | AngularJS | React Native | NodeJS | Express | Jquery | Bootstrap | Firebase | Android | Agile/Scrum | SASS | HTML5 | CSS | Jest | Enzyme | React-testing-library | Quill | BabylonJS | WebGL | Redux | webpack | Lodash | Git | NPM | Yarn

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

## Raw Engineering Pvt. ltd - Mumbai, India

March 2019 - now

### Sr. Application Engineer

- Revamped an entire webportal from AngularJS to ReactJS.
- Used Typescript to maintain the SDK developed for clients like the NBA.
- Worked and implemented Google Maps for ReactJS for the webportal.
- Created a custom Redux like component with custom events from scratch with React context API's.
- Architected and helped develop React components from scratch like Search, Dropdown & Dropdown tags.
- Developed & delivered complex systems. Worked with designers, business analysts, and product managers to estimate and plan projects in an Agile environment.
- Created an open source GDPR compliant generic Cookie consent prompt sdk using Vanilla Javascript. This SDK can be integrated in any website and it will delete cookies according to the user preference.

### Built.io Pvt. ltd - Mumbai, India

Jan 2017 - November 2018

## Jr. Application Engineer

- Implemented features like Import/Export in excel, implemented rich text editors like Redactor & Quill.
- Involved in updating gulp to webpack as a requirement, worked with AngularJS.
- Handled the creation of SDK's & connected to Built.io Backend and developed it's adapter. (
  Platforms worked with: Sublime, Advance JavaScript, Built.io Backend)
- Worked with Node.js and Implemented "Sign in" logins & connected to Box API. ( Platforms worked with: Sublime, Postman, Node.js Express, Nun-jucks, Dropbox)

#### **EDUCATION:**

## **University of Mumbai**

Jan 2013 - December 2016

Master in Computer Applications (MCA)